Preliminary Guide to the Arthur H. Lyons Papers, 1891-1933
Arthur H. Lyons papers 1891-1933
Lyons, Arthur H.
3.0 Linear Feet 15 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Arthur H. Lyons Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2002.
Biographical Note
Railroad employee and resident of New London, Conn., who traveled throughout the Northeast and the South. He was usually joined on the trips by his wife, Nettie, and son, Chelsea.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises seven bound typescript volumes containing Lyons' daily accounts of his trips. There are postcards, brochures, and other materials related to his travel that were placed in the volumes. Destinations include Washington, D.C.; New York City; Boston; Nashville; Charleston, S.C.; Jacksonville, Fla.; the 1933 World's Fair in Chicago; the White Mountains; and the Adirondacks. Topics include destinations, the people he meets, hotels, train travel, and scenery. The collection also contains a postcard scrapbook; a pamphlet by James M. Gillis entitled, The Ku-Klux Klan (1922); and a bound typescript short story entitled The Irony of Fate, which fictionalizes Lyons' father's participation in and life immediately after the Civil War. Includes 5 black-and-white photographs. (02-046)
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Lyons, Arthur H.
Railroads -- United States -- History
Railroad travel -- United States -- History
Travel writing
United States -- Description and travel
New England -- Description and travel
Southern States -- Description and travel
United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Fiction
Scrapbooks
Black-and-white photographs
Postcards
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2002-0046
  - Untitled scrapbook, undated (Box 1)
  - A Trip to the White Mountains, 1915
  - A Glimpse of the South, 1925 (Box 2)
  - A Trip to the Adirondacks, 1924 (Box 3)
  - Vacation Travelogue: Chicago and Vermont, 1933
  - Scribblings, 1891-1908
  - Little Curly Locks Takes a Vacation, 1904
  - The Ku-Klux Klan, by James M. Gillis, 1922
  - The Irony of Fate, 1908 (Box 4)
  - A Week in Washington, 1928